Register of the Carl Landauer papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, 1907-1983
  - Professional correspondence, 1914-1980
    - Mayer, Otto G., 1972-1975 (Box-folder 18: 14)
    - McGraw Hill, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 18: 15)
    - Merritt, Max, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 18: 16)
    - Messner, Johannes, 1929-1973 (Box-folder 18: 17)
    - Meyer, Henry Cord, 1952 (Box-folder 18: 18)
    - Meyer, Julie, 1933-1953 (Box-folder 18: 19)
    - Mills College, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 18: 20)
    - Mischel, Josef H., 1934-1948 (Box-folder 19: 1)
    - Mizumachi, K., 1933 (Box-folder 19: 2)
    - Molitor, Bruno, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 19: 3)
    - Molnar, Miklos, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 19: 4)
    - Monterey Institute of Foreign Studies, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 19: 5)
    - Morgenthau, Hans J., 1962 (Box-folder 19: 6)
    - Moser, Carsten R., 1971 (Box-folder 19: 7)
    - Mossé, Robert, 1941-1968 (Box-folder 19: 8)
    - Muste, A. J., 1961-1965 (Box-folder 19: 9)
    - N - General, 1934-1969 (Box-folder 19: 10-11)
    - Nathan, Otto, 1934-1941 (Box-folder 19: 12)
    - The Nation, 1934-1968 (Box-folder 19: 13)
    - National Planning Association, 1941-1972 (Box-folder 19: 14)
    - Neisser, Hans, 1936-1969 (Box-folder 19: 15)
    - Die Neue Gesellschaft, 1955-1969 (Box-folder 19: 16)
    - Neue Volkszeitung, 1940-1948 (Box-folder 19: 17)
    - Neuloch, Margarete and Otto, 1930-1964 (Box-folder 20: 1)
    - New Leader, 1942-1972 (Box-folder 20: 2-3)
    - New York Times, 1938-1958 (Box-folder 20: 4)
    - Newhouse, Hugo, 1934 (Box-folder 20: 5)
    - Niederböster, H., 1963-1964 (Box-folder 20: 6)
    - Noak, Frithjof, 1948-1954 (Box-folder 20: 7)
    - O - General, 1967 (Box-folder 20: 8)
    - Oppenheimer, Emilie, 1934-1941 (Box-folder 20: 9)
    - Oppenheimer, Franz, 1915-1942 (Box-folder 20: 10)
    - Ortlieb, Heinz-Dietrich, 1959-1976 (Box-folder 20: 11-12, 21: 1-3)
    - Der Österreichische Volkswirt, 1934 (Box-folder 21: 4)
    - P - General, 1933-1973 (Box-folder 21: 5-7)
    - Papandreou, Andreas, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 21: 8)
    - Paul T. Borchardt correspondence, 1937-1957 (Box-folder 21: 9, 22: 1)
      Scope and Contents note
      Correspondence related to Carl Landauer's interest in the legal situation of Paul T. Borchardt, a German citizen accused of espionage by the United States government.
    - Paulsen, Andreas, 1950-1961 (Box-folder 22: 2)
    - Phi Beta Kappa Society, University of California, Berkeley, 1934 (Box-folder 22: 3)
    - Phillips, Hubert, 1933-1961 (Box-folder 22: 4)
    - Piefke, Fritz, 1949-1967 (Box-folder 22: 5)
    - Plan Age, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 22: 6)
    - Preller, Ludwig, 1971 (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - Q - General, 1935-1939 (Box-folder 22: 8)
    - Quidde, Ludwig, 1935 (Box-folder 22: 9)
    - R - General, 1928-1973 (Box-folder 22: 10-11)
    - Reichenbach, B., 1915 (Box-folder 22: 12)
    - Reichert, Irving Frederick, 1934 (Box-folder 23: 1)
    - Revue Économique Internationale, 1928 (Box-folder 23: 2)
    - Reichmann, Eva, 1932-1973 (Box-folder 23: 3-4)
    - Riesman, David, 1961-1969 (Box-folder 23: 5)
    - Ritschl, Hans, 1962-1973 (Box-folder 23: 6)
    - Russell, Ruth, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 23: 7)
    - Rycke, Laurence de, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 23: 8)
    - S - General, 1935-1975 (Box-folder 23: 9-10, 24: 1-3)
    - San Francisco Committee for Service to Emigres, 1936-1944 (Box-folder 24: 4)
    - Schaafhausen, Irma, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 24: 5)
    - Schaeffler, Rudolf, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 24: 6)
    - Schapiro, Bernhard, 1938-1941 (Box-folder 24: 7)
    - Schlesinger, Karl, 1929 (Box-folder 24: 8)
    - Schloss, Hans St., 1934-1956 (Box-folder 24: 9)
    - Schumpeter, Joseph, 1929-1937 (Box-folder 24: 10)
    - Schweinitz, Dorothea and Karl de, 1948-1952 (Box-folder 24: 11)
    - Seger, Gerhart, 1934-1965 (Box-folder 24: 12, 25: 1-2)
    - Selfhelp for German Émigrés, 1937-1941 (Box-folder 25: 3)
    - Simion, Erna, 1936-1961 (Box-folder 25: 4)
    - Social Democratic Party, 1935-1973 (Box-folder 25: 5-6)
    - Social Research, 1937-1947 (Box-folder 25: 7)
    - Socialist Party of California, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 25: 8)
    - Society of California Pioneers, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 25: 9)
    - Sohn-Rethel, Alfred, 1935-1938 (Box-folder 25: 10)
    - Solano County Free Library, 1934 (Box-folder 25: 11)
    - Sollman, Wilhelm, 1937-1941, undated (Box-folder 25: 12)
    - Sozialdemokratische Flüchtlingshilfe, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 26: 1)
    - Spryer & Company, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 26: 2)
    - Sproul, Robert, 1935 (Box-folder 26: 3)
    - Stampfer, Friedrich and Marianne, 1937-1957 (Box-folder 26: 4)
    - Stanford University, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 26: 5)
    - Staudinger, Else, 1934-1950 (Box-folder 26: 6)
    - Staudinger, Hans, 1934-1975 (Box-folder 26: 7)
    - Stern, Ernst, 1935 (Box-folder 26: 8)
    - Stern, Fritz and Hedi, 1934-1966 (Box-folder 26: 9)
    - Stolper, Wolfgang, 1935 (Box-folder 26: 10)
    - Stolper, Gustav and Toni, 1933-1978 (Box-folder 26: 11)
    - Sturmthal, Adolf, 1937-1947 (Box-folder 26: 12)
    - T - General, 1934-1970 (Box-folder 26: 13)
    - Temple Emau-El, San Francisco, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 26: 14)
    - Theodor Phillip Haas refugee correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 26: 15)
    - Thorman, Irma, 1935 (Box-folder 26: 16)
    - Tolan, John H., 1942-1945 (Box-folder 27: 1)
    - U - General, 1935-1970 (Box-folder 27: 2)
    - Union Verlag, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 27: 3)
    - United Services for New Americans, 1936-1952 (Box-folder 27: 4-5)
    - United States Department of Agriculture, 1945 (Box-folder 27: 6)
    - United States Department of the Army, 1969 (Box-folder 27: 7)
    - United States Department of Commerce, 1940-1945 (Box-folder 27: 8)
    - United States Department of Defense, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 27: 9)
    - United States Department of Justice, 1942 (Box-folder 27: 10)
    - United States Department of Labor, 1941-1955 (Box-folder 27: 11)
    - United States Department of State, 1938-1973 (Box-folder 27: 12-13)
    - University of California, Berkeley, 1933-1974 (Box-folder 28: 1-4)
      Includes correspondence related to Landauer's service on the Academic Senate and the Loyalty Oath controversy of 1949-1951.
    - University of California Press, 1949-1960 (Box-folder 28: 6)
    - V - General, 1932-1954 (Box-folder 28: 6)
    - Valkenier, Elizabeth, 1955-1961 (Box-folder 28: 7)
    - Verlag Ullstein, 1927-1935 (Box-folder 28: 8)
    - W - General, 1917-1977 (Box-folder 29: 1-3)
    - Wache, Ernst and Lucrezia, 1946-1979 (Box-folder 29: 4)
    - Waller, Peter, 1934-1954 (Box-folder 29: 5)
    - War Department, 1941-1949 (Box-folder 29: 6)
    - Weber, Adolf, 1931-1961 (Box-folder 29: 7)
    - Welk, William, 1934 (Box-folder 29: 8)
    - Werner, Alfred, 1916-1928 (Box-folder 29: 9)
    - Wilbur, Hanna Ruth, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 29: 10)
    - Witherspoon, M. M., 1934 (Box-folder 29: 11)
    - Wolfe, Bertram D., 1952-1962 (Box-folder 29: 12)
    - Wolff, Hannah, 1937-1952 (Box-folder 29: 13)
    - World Without War Council, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 30: 1)
    - Y - General, 1934-1966 (Box-folder 30: 2)
    - Young Men's Christian Association, 1934-1960 (Box-folder 30: 3)
    - Young Women's Christian Association, 1934-1938 (Box-folder 30: 4)
    - Z - General, 1934-1953 (Box-folder 30: 5)
    - Zarchin, Michael M., 1934 (Box-folder 30: 6)
    - Die Zeit, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 30: 7)
  - Personal correspondence, 1907-1983
    - General, 1914-1963 (Box-folder 31: 1)
    - Abraham Landauer estate correspondence and documents, 1928-1931 (Box-folder 31: 2, 45: 2)
    - Anna, 1946 (Box-folder 31: 3)
    - Bergmann, Rosalie, 1927 (Box-folder 31: 4)
    - Brunner, Gertrude, 1926-1952, undated (Box-folder 31: 5)
    - Feuchtwanger family, 1929-1962 (Box-folder 31: 6)
    - Herbert, 1914 (Box-folder 31: 7)
    - Ilse Landauer accident correspondence, 1945-1956 (Box-folder 31: 8)
    - Immigration correspondence and documents, 1937-1948 (Box-folder 31: 9)
    - Keller, Ernst, 1914-1924 (Box-folder 31: 10)
    - Landauer, Elsbeth, 1914-1923 (Box-folder 31: 11-12, 32: 1-3)
    - Landauer, Ernest, 1949-1951 (Box-folder 32: 4)
    - Landauer, Hilde, 1913-1933 (Box-folder 32: 5-7, 33: 1)
    - Landauer, Ilse, 1926, undated (Box-folder 33: 2)
    - Landauer, Walter, undated (Box-folder 33: 3)
    - Mayerhöfer, Alfred, 1907-1910 (Box-folder 33: 4)
    - Mohr, Ilse, 1914-1917 (Box-folder 33: 5)
    - Palm, Irmagard, 1933-1983 (Box-folder 33: 6)
    - Reichenbach, Hans, 1913-1916 (Box-folder 33: 7)
    - Stein, Adele, 1914-1938 (Box-folder 33: 8)
    - Stein, Arthur, 1914-1917 (Box-folder 33: 9-10)
    - Stein, Fritz, 1914-1916 (Box-folder 33: 11)
    - Stein, Gottgab, 1914-1917 (Box-folder 33: 12)
    - Stern, Fritz, 1914 (Box-folder 33: 13)
    - Stein, Selma, 1938-1941 (Box-folder 33: 14)
    - Wetzlar, Alex, 1950 (Box-folder 33: 15)
- Collected Correspondence, 1900-1985
  - Unidentified, 1915-1945 (Box-folder 34: 1-2)
  - Landauer, Carl, 1913-1916, undated (Box-folder 34: 3-4)
  - Wedding correspondence, 1916 (Box-folder 34: 5)
  - Stein family immigration correspondence, 1939-1941 (Box-folder 34: 6-8)
    Correspondence related to Carl Landauer's wife, Hilde Landauer's (neé Stein) extended family and their immigration to the United States.
  - Abraham Landauer, 1935, undated
    Correspondence received by Carl Landauer's father.
    - Landauer, Gertrude, 1935, undated (Box-folder 34: 9)
  - Adele Stein, 1900-1929
    Corresondence received by Carl Landauer's mother-in-law.
    - Landauer, Hilde, 1900-1915 (Box-folder 34: 10)
    - Landauer, Ilse, 1923-1929 (Box-folder 35: 1)
    - Levin, Lotte, 1927-1929 (Box-folder 35: 2)
  - Alex Wetzlar, 1908-1920, undated
    Correspondence received by Carl Landauer's cousin.
    - Landauer, Elsbeth, 1908-1920, undated (Box-folder 35: 3)
  - Alfred Werner, 1916-1932
    - General, 1916-1932 (Box-folder 35: 4)
  - Andrea and Steffan Landauer, 1966-1970
    Correspondence received by Carl Landauer's grandchildren.
    - General, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 35: 5)
  - Arthur Stein, 1902-1910
    Correspondence received by Carl Landauer's brother-in-law.
    - General, 1902-1910 (Box-folder 35: 6)
  - Doris Stein, 1938
    Correspondence received by Carl Landauer's wife, Hilde Landauer's (neé Stein) cousin.
    - General, 1938 (Box-folder 35: 7)
  - Elsbeth Landauer, 1914-1920s
    Correspondence received by Carl Landauer's mother.
    - Landauer, Carl, 1915 (Box-folder 35: 8)
    - Landauer, Fritz, circa 1916 (Box-folder 35: 9)
    - Landauer, Gertrude, 1920s (Box-folder 35: 10)
    - Landauer, Hilde, 1914-1916 (Box-folder 35: 11)
    - Mohr, Ilse, 1915, undated (Box-folder 35: 12)
    - Stein, Adele, 1914-1916 (Box-folder 35: 13)
  - Erich Mohr, 1955-1966
    Corresondence received by Carl Landauer's nephew.
    - Landauer, Carl, 1955-1966 (Box-folder 35: 14)
  - Ernest Landauer, 1962-1966
    Correspondence received by Carl Landauer's son.
    - General, 1962-1966
  - Ernst Keller, 1923
    Correspondence received by Carl Landauer's wife, Hilde Landauer's (neé Stein) uncle.
    - General, 1923 (Box-folder 35: 16)
  - Gertrude Brunner, 1918-1972
    Correspondence received by Carl Landauer's daughter.
    - General, 1926-1972 (Box-folder 35: 20, 36: 1)
    - A., Rudi, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 36: 2)
    - Anneliese, 1934 (Box-folder 36: 3)
    - Brunner, Peter, 1945 (Box-folder 36: 4)
    - Dyer-Bennet, Miriam, undated (Box-folder 36: 5)
    - Grandmother Meyer, 1918-1923 (Box-folder 36: 6)
    - Hahnewald, Helmut, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 36: 7)
    - Keller, Ernst, 1947 (Box-folder 36: 8)
    - Landauer, Carl, 1926-1966 (Box-folder 36: 9-10)
    - Landauer, Hilde, 1936-1972 (Box-folder 36: 11-12)
    - Landauer, Walter, 1943-1948 (Box-folder 36: 13, 37: 1-2)
    - Mohr, Ilse, 1948 (Box-folder 37: 3)
    - Neimoeller, Ursel, 1933-1935 (Box-folder 37: 4)
    - Pedro, 1947 (Box-folder 37: 5)
    - Stern, Fritz, 1938 (Box-folder 37: 6)
    - Wolff, Franz A., 1939 (Box-folder 37: 7)
  - Hilde Landauer, 1900-1985
    Correspondence received by Carl Landauer's wife, Hilde Landauer (neé Stein).
    - General, 1909-1983 (Box-folder 37: 8-10)
    - Writings, 1906-1911, undated (Box-folder 37: 11)
    - Bergmann, Rosalie, 1924-1927 (Box-folder 37: 12)
    - Bloch, Elsbet Marianne, 1930 (Box-folder 37: 13)
    - Brunner, Gertrude, 1925-1957 (Box-folder 37: 14)
    - Cohn, Daniel, 1916-1918 (Box-folder 37: 15)
    - Dyer-Bennet, Miriam, undated (Box-folder 37: 16)
    - Feuchtwanger, Felix, 1916 (Box-folder 38: 1)
    - Genzmer, Martha, 1912 (Box-folder 38: 2)
    - Goltz, Peter, 1985 (Box-folder 38: 3)
    - Hainebach, Otto, 1914-1916 (Box-folder 38: 4-5)
    - Horowitz, Laura, 1909-1934 (Box-folder 38: 6)
    - Kanther, Manfred, 1984 (Box-folder 38: 7)
    - Keller, Ernst, 1900-1929 (Box-folder 38: 8-9)
    - Keller, Richard, 1914-1943 (Box-folder 38: 10)
    - Keller, Rita, 1917 (Box-folder 38: 11)
    - Kohn, Alfred, 1908-1929 (Box-folder 38: 12)
    - Kracauer, Friedel, 1916-1919 (Box-folder 38: 13)
    - L., Franz, 1910-1917 (Box-folder 38: 14)
    - Laengner, Fritz, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 38: 15)
    - Landauer, Carl, 1914-1950 (Box-folder 38: 16, 39: 1-6, 40: 1-7)
    - Landauer, Elsbeth, 1914-1923 (Box-folder 40: 8)
    - Landauer, Fritz, 1914 (Box-folder 41: 1)
    - Landauer, Ilse, 1924-1933 (Box-folder 41: 2)
    - Landauer, Walter, 1926-1933 (Box-folder 41: 3)
    - Levin, Lotta, 1914-1918 (Box-folder 41: 4)
    - Malter, Wolfgang, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 41: 5)
    - Mohr, Ilse, 1911-1933 (Box-folder 41: 6-7)
    - Parish, Peter J., 1985 (Box-folder 41: 8)
    - Reichenbach, Hans, 1914 (Box-folder 41: 9)
    - Semrau, Arthur and Helene, 1911-1931 (Box-folder 41: 10-11)
    - Sobotka, Paul, 1913-1928 (Box-folder 41: 12)
    - Stein, Adele, 1911-1931 (Box-folder 42: 1-2)
    - Stein, Arthur, 1914-1917 (Box-folder 42: 3)
    - Stein, Gottgab, 1914-1929 (Box-folder 42: 4)
    - Stein, Selma, 1940 (Box-folder 42: 5)
    - Warschauer, Claire, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 42: 6)
    - Werner, Alfred, 1929-1932 (Box-folder 42: 7)
    - Wilmersdoerffer, Ernst, 1929-1931 (Box-folder 42: 8)
    - Wittebur, Klemens, 1984 (Box-folder 42: 9)
  - Ilse Landauer, 1920-1930
    - General, 1920-1930 (Box-folder 42: 10)
  - Ilse Mohr, 1905-1965
    Correspondence received by Carl Landauer's sister-in-law.
    - General, 1914-1928 (Box-folder 42: 11)
    - Landauer, Carl, 1929-1965 (Box-folder 42: 12)
    - Landauer, Hilde, 1905-1919, 1960 (Box-folder 42: 13)
    - Stein, Adele, 1920-1921 (Box-folder 42: 14)
  - Julie Meyer, 1945
    - General, 1945, undated (Box-folder 42: 15)
  - Linde Mohr, 1971-1973
    Correspondence received by Carl Landauer's niece.
    - General, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 42: 16)
  - Lotta Levin, undated
    - General, undated (Box-folder 43: 1)
  - Marius Landauer, 1966
    Correspondence received by Carl Landauer's grandson.
    - General, 1966 (Box-folder 43: 2)
  - Martha Genzer, 1930
    - Landauer, Hilde, 1930 (Box-folder 43: 3)
  - Peter Brunner, 1944-1945
    Correspondence received by Carl Landauer's son-in-law.
    - Brunner, Gertrude, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 43: 4)
  - Rita Keller, 1917-1923
    - General, 1917-1923 (Box-folder 43: 5)
  - Selma Stein, 1938-1942 (Box-folder 43: 6)
    - General, 1938-1942 (Box-folder 43: 6)
  - Walter Landauer, 1931-1944
    - General, 1931-1944 (Box-folder 43: 7)
    - Landauer, Carl, 1943-1980 (Box-folder 43: 8)
    - Landauer, Hilde, 1960-1981 (Box-folder 43: 9)
- Writings by Others, 1923-1943
  - Barrows, David P., 1943 (Box-folder 43: 10)
  - Bernhard, Georg, 1923 (Box-folder 43: 11)
  - McGaw Smyth, Howard, 1943 (Box-folder 43: 12)
  - Staudinger, Hans, undated (Box-folder 43: 13)
  - Stolper, Gustav, 1934 (Box-folder 43: 14)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box-folder 43: 15)
- Photographs, circa 1910-1915
  - Landauer, Fritz, undated (Box-folder 43: 16)
  - Landauer, Hilde, 1915 (Box-folder 43: 17)
  - Stein, Arthur, circa 1910 (Box-folder 43: 18)
  - Stein, Joh., undated (Box-folder 43: 19)
- Printed Matter, 1918-1966
  - American Council Institute of Pacific Relations report, 1937 (Box-folder 43: 20)
  - Berkeley Barter Network forms, undated (Box-folder 43: 21)
  - Blank postcards, 1918-1923, undated (Box-folder 43: 22)
  - "Dial-a-Vote," voter information guide, 1957 (Box-folder 43: 23)
  - The Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Scholars annual report, 1942 (Box-folder 43: 24)
  - John F. Kennedy assassination newspaper clippings, 1963 (Box-folder 43: 25)
  - Travel brochures, 1966 (Box-folder 43: 26)
  - Untitled fragment, undated (Box-folder 43: 27)
  - Die Neue Gesellschaft: Inhaltsübersicht Autorenverzeichnis, Sachregister der Jahrgänge 1954-1955 (Box-folder 43: 28)
  - "Sozialisten Marsch," leaflet, undated (Box-folder 43: 29)
- Sound Recordings, 1982-1983, 2009
  - Interviews of Carl Landauer by Ida Landauer, 1982-1983 (Box 44)
    Compact sound cassettes
    The descriptions of these interviews have been taken directly from Ida Landauer's labels. References to "Vati" likely refer to Carl Landauer.
    - Audiotape 1, 1982 May 23 - June 5 (Box 44)
      Access note
      Use copy reference number: 90079_a_0002170
      Heine's poems, Vati's childhood, leaving Germany, coming to Berkeley. Tape interview gives the date as 5 June 1982, but Ida Landauer gives the date as 23 May 1982.
    - Audiotape 2, 1982 June 11 (Box 44)
      Use copy reference number: 90079_a_0002171
      A discussion of German officers and systems. Touches on his activism and interest in journalism.
    - Audiotapes 3, 3A, 1982 June 12 (Box 44)
      Use copy reference number: 90079_a_0002172
      War Food Admininstration, newspapers, the mayor of Munich, Franz Feuchtwanger, family.
    - Audiotape 4, 1982 June 19-21 (Box 44)
      Use copy reference number: 90079_a_0002303
      Focuses on his parents and Nazi Germany.
    - Audiotape 5, 1982 August 8-16 (Box 44)
      Use copy reference number: 90079_a_0002304
      Vati
    - Audiotape 6, 1982 October 7-11 (Box 44)
      Use copy reference number: 90079_a_0002305
      Vati's parents. Hike with Carl Frenkl, C. Landauer - Ortler Area.
    - Audiotapes 7, 8, 1982 October 24 (Box 44)
      Use copy reference number: 90079_a_0002306
      Early political.
    - Audiotape 9, 1982 November 11-20 (Box 44)
      Use copy reference number: 90079_a_0002449
      Israel. Going to U.S.
    - Audiotape 10, 1982 December 11-27 (Box 44)
      Use copy reference number: 90079_a_0002450
      Germany. The first year communication system.
    - Audiotape 11, 1983 January 16 (Box 44)
      Use copy reference number: 90079_a_0002451
      Vati, Mutti on romantic love, and a brief discussion between Ida and a third person about unions in the South.
    - Audiotape 12, 1983 January 16 - February 6 (Box 44)
      Use copy reference number: 90079_a_0002452
      The loyalty oath and Berkeley, Mutti's mother, Ilse, Walter, etc.
    - Audiotape 13, 1983 February 21 (Box 44)
      Use copy reference number: 90079_a_0002493
      Gerti's wedding, Democrats, Free Speech Movement at Berkeley, book on social planning and the history of socialism.
    - Audiotape 14, 1983 March 6 - April 3 (Box 44)
      Use copy reference number: 90079_a_0002494
      Paul Taylor, family poems, Krober, Uncle Felix, vacations (Europe), Agathe (Vati's tutor).
    - Audiotape 15, 1983 April 3 (Box 44)
      Use copy reference number: 90079_a_0002694
      Vati's tutors - Agathe, Sabine, Adele, Miriam Dyer Bennett.
    - Audiotape 16, 1983 June 12-19 (Box 44)
      Use copy reference number: 90079_a_0002695
      Alfred Werner, Louisa Rinser, Von Puthammer.
    - Audiotape 17, 1983 July 30 - August 7 (Box 44)
      Use copy reference number: 90079_a_0002696
      Eisner. The Peaceful Revolution.
    - Audiotape 18, 1983 August 4 (Box 44)
      Use copy reference number: 90079_a_0002697
      The Peaceful Revolution. Eisner. Auer. Hoegner.
    - Audiotape 19, 1983 September 11 (Box 44)
      Use copy reference number: 90079_a_0002698
      Kiel interlude. Thomas Mann family.
    - Audiotape 20, 1983 October 2 (Box 44)
      Use copy reference number: 90079_a_0002699
      Last interview. Mutti's and Vati's early days. Mutti's family (Thorn). Mutti's impressions of socialism in America.
  - Interview of Walter Landauer about immigrating to the United States, DVD, 2009 (Box 44)